so the final step in the tomasulo's
algorithm is this right result step of
or broadcast so let's see what happens
during that step so let's say that we
have this situation where we have
already issued some instructions this
one has been dispatched and is executing
and now is the cycle when this
instruction is done and wants to
broadcast its result so what's going to
happen so the first thing that will
happen is we put the tag in this case RS
1 and the result in this case - 0.29 on
the bus so it gets broadcast to all of
these structures so as a result of the
broadcast this will reach to all of
these units now what we want to do is
write to the register file basically
this is a new value for whichever
register this ad is supposed to be
writing to and we don't have to carry
that this is going to register F 2
because reservation station 1 matches
F 2 so we know that the value is going
to F 2 so we're gonna overwrite the
value in F 2 with that so pretty much
the first step is to can override the
value in the register file so we have
changed the F 2 now because of this
match between the rat and the RS 1 we
know that F 2 should be written with
this value the next thing that happens
is we update the register allocation
table basically the entry that matches
our tag needs to be changed so that it
now points to the register file we said
that an empty rat entry will be
indicative of just going to the register
instead of waiting for something so now
we need to basically you know tag this
in a way that makes it empty usually
there is a valid bit here that just says
it's empty and the last thing we need to
do is free the reservation station that
is the reservation station whose name
matches is now marked as empty so that
it can accept a new instruction in this
case we kind of just delete stuff from
it but in real Hardware there will be a
valid bit here that says that this is an
empty reservation station so this is
what needs to happen